Beibarys Sagingaliyev

Almaty, Kazakhstan • fromaktl@gmail.com • +7 (771) 168-0098 • 23/11/1998

SUMMARY

Data Analyst with solid working experience in collecting, wrangling, visualizing, analysing and reporting the data to make a decisions. Effectively and efficiently using advanced analytical tools and techniques. Applying automation and optimization procedures to deliver the result. Diverse in knowledge and experience: have working experience in Data Engineering and Data Science. Building ETL process with Python libraries, and experienced in designing and implementing Text-To-Speech models (GlowTTS, Tacotron2).

Interested areas: Data Analytics, Data Engineering.

Working mode: remotely, or office (willing to relocate if needed)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TENGIZCHEVROIL (TCO), Atyrau, Kazakhstan Senior Data Analyst December 2021-Present

- Setting up and maintaining database, building analytical dashboard, increasing management services operations.
 Decreased calculation time of key metrics from 180 mins to 5 mins (x36 times) by automating tasks.
- Providing analysis to improve cost efficiency. Optimized the meal forecast management, which decreased meal waste and saved over \$ 220 000 in a month.
- Developing bi-weekly and monthly management reports and presentations.
- Built from scratch and automated analytical reports using Power BI and Power Query, which ensured monitoring management services.
- Serving as knowledgeable data specialist to teams from different departments, on consolidating and wrangling a data.

CYBERNET, Almaty, Kazakhstan Data Analyst and ML Engineer October 2021 - Present

Responsibilities:

Data Analysis

- Built AI voice robot performance monitoring system using Python, ClickHouse and Grafana – which is allowing to detect failures in a real-time and take immediate decisions. Increased implementational response rate for 100 percent.
- Preparing and analysing the data using Python, SQL. Automated streaming of analytical metrics (ETL) by Python.
- Visualising data on Grafana and Python libraries.
- Suggesting and making decision on potential analytical project.

ML

- Researching and implementing NVIDIA Text-to-Speech (TTS) models to use in production. Includes selecting and preparing datasets, setting hyperparameters, training and testing models.
- Designed, implemented and trained NVIDIA Tacotron2 in Uzbek language, which is now operating calls in Uzbekistan.
- Implementing and testing NVIDIA GlowTTS model, which is x2 times faster than previous model and could be used for real-time voice synthesis.

MAXINUM CONSULTING GROUP, Almaty, Kazakhstan Business Analyst

Responsibilities:

- Automated audit and analytics of small & medium sized companies.
- Prepared and manipulated data on Excel and Google Sheets.
- Analysed business processes for logistic, retail, and pharmaceutical companies.
- Made informative dashboards and visualization on Power BI and Google Data Studio.
- Worked with IT department members in establishing automation and optimization of processes.
- Mentored junior business analysts on client support tasks.

EDUCATION

KAZAKH-BRITISH TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, Almaty, Kazakhstan Sep 2021- June 2023 (apprx.) Master of Science in Data Science, Current GPA: 3.83/4.00

UNIVERSITY OF LONDON, London, UK

Nov 2017- Oct 2020

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Economics,
Honours: Second Upper-Class Honours

KAZAKH-BRITISH TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, Almaty, Kazakhstan Aug 2016- Jul 2020 Bachelor of Science in Economics

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Proficient in MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Outlook.
- Proficient in googling and finding answers.
- Working experience in Python and SQL (Postgres).
- Proficient in pandas, numpy, scipy, matplotlib Python libraries for data analysis.
- Visualization and monitoring tools Grafana, Microsoft Power BI and Google Data Studio.
- Languages: Kazakh, English, Russian and conversational Turkish.

Certificates and Achievements

- IELTS overall band 7.0, corresponds to C1 (valid until Sep 2022).
- GRE General: Quantitative reasoning 161/170 (valid until Nov 2024).
- AWS Academy ML Foundations certificate (issued May 2022).
- Coursera Yandex courses: Statistical analysis, Unsupervised learning certificate (issued May 2022).
- Kazakhstan government scholarship with stipend for bachelor and master's programs.
- KaspiLab: Data Science certificate.